Carolina Power and Light Photograph Collection PHC.68
State Archives of North Carolina
- Hurricane Ione, 19 September 1955. Series of prints and medium format 6x6 negatives depicting the aftermath and response of Carolina Power and Light to Hurricane Ione 19 September 1955 in Goldsboro and unidentified location on coast. Forty nine medium format 6x6 frames depict various scenes after the storm including, workers repairing power lines, documentation of damage to infrastructure, damage to residences and other buildings, and several pictures of people indicating recent water levels on walls. Eighteen silver gelatin prints of selected negatives are included with the negatives., PhC.68.1.472.1-18; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, Biscoe, Candor; Electrical Line Work After Ice Storm, 1960. Series of photographs depicting Carolina Power and Light crews in Raleigh, Biscoe, and Candor repairing electrical lines and clearing fallen trees and limbs after an ice storm in 1960., PhC.68.1.473.1-15; Carolina Power and Light
- Biscoe, Troy, Candor, Ice Storm 13-14 February 1960. Series of 25 silver gelatin 8x10 prints that depict an ice storm in the Biscoe-Candor, Troy, NC vicinity. Carolina Power and Light crews are seen repairing down electrical lines, damaged electrical infrastructure is thoroughly documented, close shots of linemen working on electrical lines, residences are seen with leaning trees over electrical lines, a tree is seen bent down by weight of ice and leaning on a car, office scene with CP and L workers organizing and talking on phone, the Weeks and Andrews Construction crew is pictured posing tog, PhC.68.1.474.1-25; Carolina Power and Light
- Ice Storm, Dillon Vicinity, 26-27 January 1966. Series of 8 silver gelatin 8x10 prints depict Carolina Power and Light crews working to repair electrical lines in the Dillon, SC vicinity. Advertisements for South of the Border are seen with linemen repairing equipment, Line men are seen climbing up a ladder with a saw to remove a limb leaning on power lines, other various scenes of workers repairing electrical infrastructure. 26-27 January 1966, PhC.68.1.475.1-10; Carolina Power and Light
- Ice Storms, Henderson, Oxford, and Roxboro, NC, December 1967. Series of 11 silver gelatin 8x10 prints of ice storm damage and repair in the Henderson, Oxford, and Roxboro vicinity. Linemen are seen in bucket trucks and on ladders repairing electric lines while ice covers the surrounding trees. One photograph is included of linemen working on electrical lines at the intersection of Rosemary and Hillsborough Streets in Raleigh, NC. All other images appear to be in the Henderson, Roxboro, Oxford vicinity. December 1967, PhC.68.1.476.1-15; Carolina Power and Light
- Ice Storms, Goldsboro 1968. Series of contact sheets from original negatives of various work done on electrical lines by Carolina Power and Light in 1968. Possibly in the Goldsboro, NC vicinity., PhC.68.1.477; Carolina Power and Light
- Rockingham and Wadesboro, NC Ice Storm c. 1969. Large series of 35 mm negatives depicting Carolina Power and Light line crews repairing electric power lines as a result of winter/ice storms in various locations including Rockingham and Wadesboro, NC. Also included are 12 8x10 silver gelatin prints. c. 1969, PhC.68.1.478.1-12; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Morgan and Wilmington Street, Snow Storm 2-3 April 1915. Pictured is the intersection of Morgan and Wilmington Streets looking East down Morgan Street in Raleigh, NC. Deep snow is seen covering the roadways a car can be seen in the distance, turning down Blount Street. Power poles lining Morgan Street have fallen away from street against buildings. First Baptist Church can be seen on right c. 1915, PhC.68.1.479.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Looking East Down Hargett Street, Snow Storm 2-3 April 1915. View looking east down Hargett Street in Raleigh, NC. Buildings on south side of Hargett Street are most visible. Snow is seen covering the roadways and buildings. Power poles have fallen into street. Barricades is seen, closing off the street to traffic. 2-3 April 1915, PhC.68.1.480; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Snowstorm, 1400 Block Hillsborough. PhC68.1.481.1 -View of Hillsborough Street looking East from the 1400 block taken in 1915 after a snow storm. The large park-like area on the right side of the photo is part of the St. Marys campus. The house on the far left of the frame is 115 W Park Dr. in Cameron Park. In the middle of the photo is 1306 Hillsborough St. and the house on the right side is where present day (July 2015) IHOP is located., PhC.68.1.481.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Snow Storm Tower Collapse at Method, 2-3 April 1915. Pictured is a substation, possibly at Method Road in Raleigh. A tower is seen collapsed on its side. The ground is covered with snow. c. 1915, PhC.68.1.482; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Tower Collapse, Cannon Avenue and Saunders Street, Snow Storm, 2-3 April 1915. Toppled and leaning power poles and a collapsed electrical tower are seen near the intersection of Cannon Avenue (no longer in existence, present day vicinity of Dorothea Drive) and Saunders Street. Snow is seen on roadways, houses are seen lining the street. 2-3 April 1915, PhC.68.1.483; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Power Poles Down Between Method and A and M College, Hillsborough Street, 2-3 April 1915. Hillsborough Street in Raleigh, NC is seen looking East from approximately the 2500 block. Patterson Hall can be seen in the far distance on the right side of the road. Residences are seen in foreground as power poles are seen lying on the ground crossing roadway. Snow is seen covering the ground. c. 1915, PhC.68.1.484; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Tower Collapse, Cannon Avenue and West Street, Snow Storm, 2-3 April 1915. Three men are seen surrounding a collapsed electrical tower at the intersection of Cannon Avenue (no longer in existence, present day vicinity of Dorothea Drive) looking north-east up West Street. Snow is seen on roadways, houses are seen lining the street. 2-3 April 1915, PhC.68.1.485; Carolina Power and Light
- Munitions Explosion, Selma, NC, March 1942. Landscape depicting the destruction seen in Selma, NC after a munitions explosion. Group of people are seen on right side of frame, surveying damage. Wreckage and debris is spread over the entire landscape. March 1942, PhC.68.1.486; Carolina Power and Light
- Tornado, Possibly Lumberton, NC 8 April 1957. Several views of a fallen 110 KV tower in a rural area possibly near Lumberton, NC. The fallen tower is seen from various angles. Linemen are seen erecting a new tower. 8 April 1957, PhC.68.1.487.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC Area, Tornado, November 1966. The aftermath of a tornado in Garner, NC is seen. Furniture and debris is seen littering the ground outside of a trailer park. Debris is also seen hanging from overhead power lines. A Garner, NC fire engine is seen parked near site of destruction. Mobile homes are seen in the background. November 1966, PhC.68.1.488.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Rockingham, Laurinburg Area, Tornado Damage c. 1940s. Series of images depicting the destruction caused to Carolina Power and Light electrical towers after a tornado in the Laurinburg-Rockingham, NC area. Towers are seen toppled over in rural area. Workers are seen assessing the damage. Barns, residences, and other buildings are seen in background. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.489.1-17; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Snow Storm, Hillsborough Street, NC State, 2-3 April 1915, PhC.68.1.490.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh, NC, Windstorm Damage, 13 February 1966. Windstorm damage is seen in Raleigh, NC. Trees are seen broken, branches and debris on ground. Rowland Boyd and Bob Watson are seen sitting at a desk looking over paper plans. James Powell and Alvin Gates are seen standing in an office, working. 13 February 1966, PhC.68.1.491.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Environmental Studies c. 1969. Men are seen in boat off of the coast of North Carolina catching and studying what look like Shrimp. The sea life is seen being caught, put into glass jars, and recorded. Men are also seen studying samples in a laboratory with microscopes. c. 1969, PhC.68.1.492; Carolina Power and Light
- Earth Day, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 22-23 April 1970. Earth Day proceedings are seen on the campus of University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Citizens and students are seen participating in the event. People are seen placing cans in trash bags, large group of bikes is seen parked in open area, speakers are seen speaking to group of students, various scenes around the UNC Chapel Hill campus of students and citizens participating in Earth Day. 22-23 April 1970, PhC.68.1.493; Carolina Power and Light
- Environmental Research, 2 June 1971. Environmental research employees are seen in a small boat with equipment, under high power lines. Possibly Shearon Harris Reservoir. 2 June 1971, PhC.68.1.494; Carolina Power and Light
- Environmental, Scrap Shredders, February 1972. One medium format roll of film with contact print and one 35mm roll of film with contact print of a scrap shredder plant. Automobiles and scrap metal are seen being recycled. Plant is next to a rail line. Rail cars are seen taking away processed metal. Also includes a clipping describing the purpose of the plant. February 1972, PhC.68.1.495.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Asheville Sewage Treatment Plant, August 1972. Series of 7 5x7 photographs with captions depict the Asheville sewage treatment plant and several crucial components of its workings. R. L. Cunningham, superintendent of the plant, is seen in several pictures posing with various pieces of equipment and with Greer Johnson, engineer-manager for the plant. Also included is a roll of 35mm film with contact sheet and a letter describing the purpose and benefits of the treatment plant. August 1972, PhC.68.1.496.1-8; Carolina Power and Light
- Electrostatic Precipitator at Sutton Plant, Wilmington, NC. 27 December 1972. Pictured is Carolina Power and Light's electrostatic precipitator is seen at the Sutton Plant near Wilmington, NC. Also included is a description of the device and its benefit. 27 December 1972, PhC.68.1.497; Carolina Power and Light
- Woodpecker Nest on Power Pole, January 1973. A Carolina Power and Light electric pole is pictured with a section cut from the old pole it replaced. The small section attached to the new pole has a woodpecker nest in it. Men are also seen in the pictures. A child is seen in one photo on the shoulders of one of the men. January 1973, PhC.68.1.498.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Waterville, NC, Walters Hydroelectric Plant, c. 1950s. 19 medium format negatives depicting the Waterville, NC vicinity including Mt. Sterling and the Walters Hydroelectric plant. Homes, buildings (including post office) and people are seen around Waterville, NC. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.499.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Miscellaneous pictures of people. Men are seen looking over plans outdoors while a child plays, Tom Pritchett is seen writing on a clipboard, a boy is seen holding up a fish while two men look on, two boys are seen standing between two grown men outdoors. c. 1970s, PhC.68.1.500.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Resource Use Conference, UNC, c. 1960s. Two men are seen sitting at a desk with a paper while 6 men stand over them looking down at paper. All unidentified. c. 1960s, PhC.68.1.501; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh Chamber of Commerce Group Board Bus, c. 1960s Pictured is a group of 16 men lined up against a bus in front of the Sir Walter Hotel in Raleigh, NC. Back of photo is captioned, "Chamber of Commerce group prior to embarking on a trip to Columbia, SC to inspect produce market." c. 1960s, PhC.68.1.502; Carolina Power and Light
- Beauty Contest c. 1930s. Pictured is approximately 25 women in bathing suits all with numbers on them. They are standing on a structure and are probably part of some kind of beauty contest. c. 1930s. Includes original 8x10 negative (safety film)., PhC.68.1.503; Carolina Power and Light
- Beauty Contest c. 1930s. Seven women are seen in formal dress on a stage wearing numbers. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.504; Carolina Power and Light
- Parade Float- Dixie's Playground, Wrightsville Beach, NC c. 1940s. Eight people are seen on a parade float in Wrightsville Beach, NC. They are wearing a type of sash. Parade float reads, "Wrightsville Beach, Dixie's Playground". c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.505; Carolina Power and Light
- Governor Robert Gregg Cherry. Pictured is North Carolina Governor Robert Gregg Cherry. He is seen seated at a desk with a telephone receiver up to his ear. c. 1945, PhC.68.1.506; Carolina Power and Light
- Football Players, Unidentified, c. 1940s. Two football players are picture outdoors near a piece of practice equipment. They are both seen in uniform, posing for the camera. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.507; Carolina Power and Light
- Boy Scouts Camping Trip Sponsored by Carolina Power and Light c. 1950s. A group of Boy Scouts are seen in Asheville, NC preparing to board a bus for a camping trip sponsored by Carolina Power and Light. The boys are seen in uniform gathered together with luggage preparing to leave, in a line boarding the bus, scouts are seen in the windows of the bus preparing to leave, camping in the woods, preparing a campfire, and touring an Walters Hydroelectric plant in Waterville, NC. Troops 28, 1 (present day 701), and 43 are seen. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.508.1-8; Carolina Power and Light
- Man Working in Plant c. 1950s. John Gunter manipulates a chain operated feedwater valve on the eighth stage feedwater heater of Unit 2 at Weatherspoon in September of 1950, PhC.68.1.509; Carolina Power and Light
- Carbonton Hydroelectric Station, Carbonton, NC c. 1930s-1950s. Various views of the Carbonton Hydroelectric plant in Carbonton, NC on the Deep River. Photographs span from 1930 to 1953 and includes a photograph of Bill Blakely, the superintendent in 1953, standing in front of the plant. The plant is also pictured in 1939 during a flood. c. 1930s-1950s, PhC.68.1.510.1-7; Carolina Power and Light
- Goldsboro Iron and Metal Co. Advertisement with Power Pole. Two large power poles with a transformer supported between them is seen on the side of a street in front of an advertisement for Goldsboro Iron and Metal Co. An automobile is seen in view. c. 1930, PhC.68.1.511; Carolina Power and Light
- Siler City, NC Electric Plant Ruins c. 1963. Reuben DuBose and George Siler are seen around the site of the first electric generating plant in the community. c. 1963, PhC.68.1.512.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Avery Street Substation High Water, Man With Horse and Carriage c. 1928. A man is seen next to a high river standing near a horse and carriage. Photograph is captioned Avery Street Substation, Asheville; however, the station does not appear in photograph. c. 1928, PhC.68.1.513; Carolina Power and Light
- Laurinburg, NC Substation, July 1951. Larry Cartwright and Tom Ingram are seen inside a control room at the Laurinburg Substation. They are seen sitting at a desk and standing, looking at an electrical schematic board. July 1951, PhC.68.1.514; Carolina Power and Light
- Substation, Method, June 1951. The interior of the Method Road Substation in Raleigh, NC is seen. Worker, O. A. Palmer is seen loading paper into some sort of data recorder. June 1951, PhC.68.1.515.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Canton, NC Substation, October 1950. L. J. Cannon, Chief Division Dispatcher at the Canton, NC Carolina Power and Light substation is seen pointing at the dispatcher's board in an office. October 1950, PhC.68.1.516; Carolina Power and Light
- Steam Plant Interior, Raleigh, NC c. 1915-1920. Pictured is the interior of the Raleigh Steam Plant located on West Jones Street in Raleigh, NC. Machinery and equipment is seen. A formally dressed man and a worker can be seen posing in the picture. c. 1915-1920, PhC.68.1.517; Carolina Power and Light
- Steam Plant Interior, Raleigh, NC. c. 1909. Boiler equipment is seen inside the Raleigh Steam Plant on West Jones Street in Raleigh, NC. 15 May 1909, PhC.68.1.518; Carolina Power and Light
- Steam Plant Interior, Raleigh, NC 25 October 1910. Pictured is the interior of the Raleigh Steam Plant on West Jones Street in Raleigh, NC 25 October 1910. Industrial equipment is seen in use. Two workers are seen among the equipment., PhC.68.1.519; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh Steam Plant, Carolina Power and Light, Raleigh, NC c. 1925. Pictured is the Raleigh Steam Plant on West Jones Street in Raleigh, NC c. 1925. Automobiles and carriages are seen on Jones street looking east while the railroad gates are down. These cars are presumably waiting for a train to pass, although no train is pictured. Many overhead electric lines can be seen in the area. The Carolina Power and Light general garage is seen in the back ground., PhC.68.1.520; Carolina Power and Light
- Steam Plant Interior, Raleigh, NC c. 1915-1920. Pictured is the interior of the Raleigh Steam Plant located on West Jones Street in Raleigh, NC. Machinery and equipment is seen. Two workers can be seen posing amongst the equipment. c. 1915-1920, PhC.68.1.521; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Steam Plant, Raleigh, NC, July 1911. Pictured is the Raleigh Steam Plant on West Jones Street in Raleigh, NC c. 1911. Many overhead electric lines and cables can be seen. Four smoke stacks are seen coming from the steam plant. They are secured with numerous cables. July 1911, PhC.68.1.522; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Steam Plant, Raleigh, NC, c. 1914. Carolina Power and Light substation and steam reserve plant is pictured from the rear of the building looking north from two slightly different angles. Large reserve plant can be seen on the right side of frame. An automobile is seen near the building. One photograph and one magazine clipping outlining the company's current status. c. 1914, PhC.68.1.523; Carolina Power and Light
- Power Plant, Raleigh, NC c. 1963. Pictured is a power plant with black smoke coming from smoke stacks. Raleigh, NC 14 January 1963, PhC.68.1.524; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Southeast Station, Raleigh, NC c. 1920s. Pictured is the interior of the Southeastern Carolina Power and Light plant in Raleigh, NC with industrial lighting equipment seen. Back is captioned, "Raleigh, S. E. Station Series Luminous Arc Lighting System". c. 1920s, PhC.68.1.525; Carolina Power and Light
- Pinehurst Area Recreation, Sandhills, NC c. 1930s-1950s, PhC.68.1.526.1-10; Carolina Power and Light
  - Pinehurst Area Recreation, Sandhills, NC c. 1930s-1950sPhotograph is captioned, "The Pinehurst Gun Club - with its traps and skeet ranges, adds another sport for the visitors to the Sandhills." c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.01; Carolina Power and Light
  - Formally dressed men are seen wearing top hats riding horses toward camera down a dirt road in Pinehurst, NC. c. 1930s, PhC.68.1.526.02; Carolina Power and Light
  - Scenic picture of people playing golf on a golf course at Pinehurst, NC. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.03; Carolina Power and Light
  - People are seen on a golf green putting while a large crowd circles around the green. Clubhouse at Southern Pines, NC can be seen. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.04; Carolina Power and Light
  - Photo is captioned, "Pinehurst Country Club- Three 18 hole golf courses- two 18 hole putting course, tennis courts, dining and dances, is the meeting place of the Winter Cottage Colony and the visitors staying at the many hotels in the Sandhills. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.526.05; Carolina Power and Light
  - Scenic picture of people playing golf at Pinehurst Country Club in Pinehurst, NC. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.526.06; Carolina Power and Light
  - Photograph is captioned, "Riding party leaving the Carolina Hotel in Pinehurst, NC". c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.07; Carolina Power and Light
  - Photograph is captioned, "Field trials, held by the Pinehurst Field Trial Club attract the leading dog owners and their dogs to the Sandhills. This photo shows a brace of dogs before being released during the trials here this season." c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.08; Carolina Power and Light
  - Men are seen on horses in an open field with a pack of dogs alongside. Possibly fox hunting. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.09; Carolina Power and Light
  - Men are seen on horses in an open field with a pack of dogs alongside. Possibly fox hunting. c. 1950s, PhC.68.1.526.10; Carolina Power and Light
- Carolina Power and Light Bowling League c. 1937. The Carolina Power and Light bowling league is pictured in formation, at a bowling alley. Front row; Woodall, Watkins, Stewart, Gordon, Stallings, Lutz, Bradley, Bostick. Second Row; Fry, Villiers, Jenkins, Jones, Williams, Lang, Hanchey, Thopson, Miller, Sumner, Harvin, Johnson, McCabe. Back row; Wilson, Robinson, Hicks, Bazemore, Biggs, Kimball, Skaale. 1Apr 1937, PhC.68.1.527; Carolina Power and Light
- Raleigh Softball Team-Group Picture c. 1942. Pictured is the Carolina Power and Light Softball team. They are sitting and standing in uniform, in formation for a group portrait. c. 1942, PhC.68.1.528; Carolina Power and Light
- Womanless Wedding, May 1950. Series of images depicting a wedding ceremony with no women. Men are dressed as women as a mock wedding is held. May 1950, PhC.68.1.529; Carolina Power and Light
- Play (Theatre), Carolina Power and Light c. 1940s. Pictured are various scenes from an unidentified play. Man and woman actors are seen on stage acting with a set made to look like a living room. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.530.1-4; Carolina Power and Light
- Waynesville Country Club c.1940s. Pictured is a scene at the Waynesville Country Club. Two men are seen on horses talking to a golfer on the golf course as a woman looks on from a shaded patio. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.531; Carolina Power and Light
- Woman's Softball Team c. 1940s. A woman's softball team is pictured huddling with their coach, Harry Paxton. Lucille Rights and Pauline Morrison are also pictured standing together, laughing. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.532.1-2; Carolina Power and Light
- Baseball Teams c. 1920s-1930s. Three baseball teams are seen posing in formation. One is identified as possibly the Kelvinator team, one is unidentified with a large 'K' on uniforms, and one is a Carolina Power and Light team from Asheville, NC. c. 1920s-1930s, PhC.68.1.533.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Testing Life of Lamps, Photo-Cells, Squirrel Resistant Transformers. c. 1950s. A Carolina Power and Light employee is seen indoors and outdoors testing various equipment. The man is seen testing the life of lightbulbs in a dark laboratory. He is also seen testing photocells and squirrel resistant transformers with model electric poles and transformers. c. 1950, PhC.68.1.534.1-11; Carolina Power and Light
- Scenic Mountain Views, Photos by Elliot Lyman Fisher, Asheville, NC c. 1930s., PhC.68.1.535.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Scenic Mountain Views, North Carolina, c. 1930s. A man and woman are seen standing by an automobile looking out over the mountains. Captioned, "Looking into the North Carolina portion of the Great Smokey Mountains National park, near Asheville NC. This view is from the noted Sky Line Drive to Clingmans Dome, highest peak in the park"., PhC.68.1.536.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Scenic Mountain Views, North Carolina, c. 1960s., PhC.68.1.537.1-5; Carolina Power and Light
- Scenic Mountain Views, Lake Lure, Grandfather Mountain, NC c. 1940s., PhC.68.1.538.1-3; Carolina Power and Light
- Man Fishing, Pisgah National Forest. c. 1940s. A man is seen fishing in a stream in the Pisgah National Forest in Western North Carolina. c. 1940s, PhC.68.1.539; Carolina Power and Light